Guide to the Sarah G. Jacobson Papers MSS.157
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Accretion 2008 - Series VII: Printed Material, 1990-2004; 158852
  - Time Out New York, Issue 437, February 12-19, 2004, 158856 (Box 23, Folder 240)
  - Maximum Rock 'n Roll, # 252, May 2004, 158855 (Box 23, Folder 241)
  - BUST Magazine, Summer 2004, 158854 (Box 23, Folder 242)
  - Venus Zine, Issue # 11, Winter 2001, 158853 (Box 23, Folder 243)
- Accretion 2008 - Series VIII: Teaching Materials, 2001-2003; 158849
  - College Lecture Files, 2001-2003; 158851 (Box 21, Folder 161)
  - Teaching Annex Advertisement, Undated; 158850 (Box 21, Folder 162)
- Accretion 2008 - Series X: Miscellaneous, 1984-2004; 158818
  - Subseries A: Assorted Personal Items, 1984-2002; 158830
    - "Bat Mitzvah Stuff", 1984; 158848 (Box 21, Folder 163)
    - Ticket Stubs and Programs, 1988-2001; 158847 (Box 21, Folder 164)
    - Season's Greetings Calendar, 1988; 158846 (Box 21, Folder 166)
    - Calvin and Hobbes 16-Month Calendar, 1988-1989; 158845 (Box 21, Folder 167)
    - Charles Burns Calendar, 1994; 158844 (Box 21, Folder 168)
    - San Francisco Underground Bands Calendar, 1995; 158843 (Box 21, Folder 169)
    - The Wagons of Steel Calendar, 1995; 158842 (Box 21, Folder 170)
    - The WRS Calendar, 1998; 158841 (Box 21, Folder 172)
    - Skid Row A Go-Go Game, 1993; 158840 (Box 21, Folder 173)
    - Palm Pilot Manual and Correspondence, 1999; 158839 (Box 21, Folder 174)
    - NYC Maps, 2000-2002; 158838 (Box 21, Folder 175)
    - Personal Basic Principles, 2001; 158837 (Box 21, Folder 176)
    - Feng Shui House Plans, Undated; 158836 (Box 21, Folder 177)
    - "Made a searching and fearless moral inventoy of ourselves", Undated; 158835 (Box 21, Folder 178)
    - Assorted Blank Postcards, Undated; 158834 (Box 21, Folder 179)
    - Assorted Ephemera, Undated; 158833 (Box 21, Folder 180)
    - "Sarah's Video Cassette Chart", Undated; 158832 (Box 21, Folder 182)
    - Assorted Photographs and Negatives, Undated; 158831 (Box 21, Folder 183)
  - Subseries B: Personal Correspondence, 1981-2004; 158824
    - Personal Correspondence 1, 1981-1987; 158829 (Box 21, Folder 184)
    - Personal Correspondence 2, 1988-1989; 158828 (Box 21, Folder 185)
    - Personal Correspondence 3, 1990-1993; 158827 (Box 21, Folder 186)
    - Personal Correspondence 4, 1994-1999; 158826 (Box 21, Folder 187)
    - Personal Correspondence 5, 2000-2004; 158825 (Box 21, Folder 188)
  - Subseries C: Objects, Undated; 158819
    - Car Accident Latex Bracelet, Undated; 158823 (Box 23, Object ID: 157.2.0049)
    - White Axcess Pouch with Assorted Pins, Undated; 158822 (Box 23, Object ID: 157.2.0050)
    - Peanuts Lunch Box, Undated; 158821 (Box 23, Object ID: 157.2.0051)
    - Flower Coaster, Undated; 158820 (Box 23, Object ID: 157.2.0052)
      This item was originally found among the Smiley Face Collection.
- Accretion 2008 - Series XII: Student Materials, 1976-1993; 158772
  - Subseries A: Elementary School - High School Documents, 1976-1989; 158797
    - Report Cards, 1976-1989; 158817 (Box 22, Folder 189)
    - Standardized Test Reports, 1979-1989; 158816 (Box 22, Folder 190)
    - Awards and Certificates, 1981-1989; 158815 (Box 22, Folder 191)
    - "A Bent Rainbow in Oz" by Sarah Jacobson, 1982; 158814 (Box 22, Folder 192)
    - Music Notebook, 1982-1983; 158813 (Box 22, Folder 193)
    - Writing Files, 1983-1984; 158812 (Box 22, Folder 194)
    - Gifted Community College Program, 1984; 158811 (Box 22, Folder 195)
    - Music Notebook, "Original Songs", 1985; 158810 (Box 22, Folder 196)
    - Creative Writing Class Assignments, 1986; 158809 (Box 22, Folder 197)
    - Creative Writing Files, 1986-1988; 158808 (Box 22, Folder 198)
    - NFTY In Israel Bulletin #3, 1987; 158807 (Box 22, Folder 199)
    - Sketch Diary, Undated; 158806 (Box 22, Folder 202)
    - High School Class Photo, Undated; 158805 (Box 22, Folder 203)
    - Notebook, 1987; 158804 (Box 22, Folder 204)
    - Sheet Music and Original Lyrics, Undated; 158803 (Box 22, Folder 205)
    - Music Notebook, Undated; 158802 (Box 22, Folder 206)
    - High School Writing, 1988-1989; 158801 (Box 22, Folder 207)
    - Cinema Arts Class Materials and Assignments, Undated; 158800 (Box 22, Folder 208)
    - Notebook, "Film Notes", 1988; 158799 (Box 22, Folder 209)
    - "Franklin High School" Story by Sarah Jacobson, Undated; 158798 (Box 22, Folder 210)
  - Subseries B: Collegiate Documents, 1989-1993; 158775
    - Bard College, Schoolwork and Application Materials, 1989-1992; 158796 (Box 22, Folder 211)
    - Bard College, Report Cards & Application Materials, 1989-1991; 158795 (Box 22, Folder 212)
    - Sarah's Going Away Party Flyer, 1989; 158794 (Box 22, Folder 213)
    - Bard College, Student ID Card, 1990-1991; 158793 (Box 22, Folder 214)
    - Bard College, Creative Writing, Scripts, and Flyers, 1989-1991; 158792 (Box 22, Folder 215)
    - Bard College, Art History Notebook, 1989-1991; 158791 (Box 22, Folder 216)
    - Bard College, Notebook, 1989-1991; 158790 (Box 22, Folder 217)
    - Bard College, Notebook, 1989-1991; 158789 (Box 22, Folder 218)
    - Bard College, Notebook, 1989-1991; 158788 (Box 22, Folder 219)
    - Bard College, Notebook, 1989-1991; 158787 (Box 22, Folder 220)
    - Date Log Book, 1991; 158786 (Box 22, Folder 221)
    - Address Book, Notebook, 1991; 158785 (Box 22, Folder 222)
    - Bard College Film Committee Materials, 1999; 158784 (Box 22, Folder 223)
    - "Sarah's Life in 366 Simple Days" Pocket Diary, 1992; 158783 (Box 22, Folder 224)
    - SF Art Institute, "This Is Stuff In My Notebook!" Notebook, 1992; 158782 (Box 22, Folder 225)
    - Beverly Hills, 90210 Special 1992-93 Student Planner, 1992-1993; 158781 (Box 22, Folder 226)
    - SF Art Institute, Notebook, 1992-1993; 158780 (Box 22, Folder 227)
    - SF Art Institute, "Art School Chicks" Contact Sheets and Storyboard, 1992-1994; 158779 (Box 22, Folder 228A)
    - SF Art Institute, "History of Cinema" Notebook, 1992-1994; 158778 (Box 23, Folder 229)
    - Notebook, Undated; 158777 (Box 23, Folder 231)
    - New School University, "Acting for Filmmakers" Student Materials, 2003; 158776 (Box 23, Folder 232)
  - Subseries C: Photographs, Undated; 158773
    - SF Art Institute Photographs, 1992-1994; 158774 (Album 32)
- Accretion 2008 - Oversize Series IV: Professional Projects, 158769
  - Subseries B: Sleaze, 158770
    - "Chicks in Rock" Collected Press Clips, 1980-2002; 158771 (Box 24, Folder 73B)
- Accretion 2008 - Oversize Series X: Miscellaneous, 158764
  - Subseries A: Assorted Personal Items, 158765
    - James Dean Calendar, 1987; 158768 (Box 24, Folder 165)
    - At A Glance Calendar, 1998; 158767 (Box 24, Folder 171)
    - Assorted Posters and Flyers, Undated; 158766 (Box 24, Folder 181)
- Accretion 2008 - Oversize Series XII: Student Materials, 158757
  - Subseries A: Elementary - High School Documents, 158761
    - "Sarah in Israel," Sketch Diary, 1987; 158763 (Box 24, Folder 200)
    - Sketchpad, 1988; 158762 (Box 24, Folder 201)
  - Subseries B: Collegiate Documents, 158758
    - SF Art Institute, "Art School Chicks" Contact Sheets, 1992-1994; 158760 (Box 24, Folder 228B)
    - SF Art Institute, Chicago International Film Festival Certificate of Merit for I Was A Teenage Serial Killer, 1993; 158759 (Box 24, Folder 230)
- Series XIII: 2018 Accretion, 1953-2012; 14 videocassettes (vhs); 17 videodiscs (dvd); 30 videocassettes (minidv); 7 sound discs (cd); 4 sound cassettes (dat); 1 audiocassette; 1 videoreels (1/2 inch)
  Arrangement
  This series has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
  This accretion includes production materials from Sarah G. Jacobson's independent film projects and freelance writing. The bulk of the material relates to Jacobson's professional career, primarily the production of her films Mary Jane's Not A Virgin Anymore and I Was A Teenage Serial Killer. These materials consist of notebooks, photographs, correspondence, 68 video recordings, and 8 born-digital CD-R's from her directing projects, as well as collections of Jacobson's published writing. Photography from the production of Mary Jane's Not A Virgin Anymore, multiple Sundance Film Festivals, and a launch party of a music video for the British punk band Fluffy are also present. Jacobson's freelance writing on modern film from 1995 to 1998 published in fanzines, underground film and music publications such as Filth and Film Threat, as well as commercial publications Sassy and YM represent her contributions to film journalism. In addition, this accretion includes classwork and notebooks from 1987 to 2004.
  - Notebook, 1985-2012 (Box 35, Folder 1-6, 9-22, Box 37, Folder 1-21, 29, Box 38, Folder 2-3, Box 36, Folder 1-6, 8-20)
  - Photographs, 1995-1998 (Box 38, Folder 4-7, 10-12, Box 37, Folder 26-28)
  - Merla in Oz, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - Sympathy letters, 2004 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Ohio, Pennsylvania, 1953-2012 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - SLAA, Undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - ACLU, 2003 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - My Hipster Indie Film Column, 1995-1997 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Glasses, Undated (Box 40)
  - Bachelors degree, 1994 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Posters, Undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Audiovisual material, Undated (Box 39)